One Final Night to Save the Day.
Night at the Museum: Secret of the Tomb is a adventure,
comedy, fantasy film directed by Shawn Levy.
When the magic powers of The Tablet of Ahkmenrah begin to die out, Larry Daley spans the globe, uniting favorite
and new characters while embarking on an epic quest to save the magic before it is gone forever.
Larry Daley / Laaa, played by Ben Stiller.
Theodore Roosevelt, played by Robin Williams.
Jedediah Smith, played by Owen Wilson.
Octavius, played by Steve Coogan.
Dr. McPhee, played by Ricky Gervais.
Sir Lancelot, played by Dan Stevens.
Night at the Museum: Secret of the Tomb is a 2014 American fantasy comedy film
directed by Shawn Levy and written by David Guion and Michael Handelman.
It is the third (and final live-action) installment in the Night at the Museum film series, a sequel to  Night at
the Museum: Battle of the Smithsonian (2009), and the final installment in the original trilogy.
The film stars Ben Stiller in the lead role, Robin Williams,
Owen Wilson, Dan Stevens and Ben Kingsley.
In the film, security guard Larry Daley must travel to London to return the Tablet of Ahkmenrah, an
Egyptian artifact which causes the exhibits to come to life, before the magic disappears.
Principal photography of Secret of the Tomb took place from January to
May 2014 in London, England and British Columbia, Canada.
The film premiered on December 11, 2014, at New York City's Ziegfeld Theater and was
released in the United States on December 19, 2014, by 20th Century Fox.
Secret of the Tomb grossed over $363 million at the box office, becoming the
lowest-grossing film in the series, and like its predecessors, received mixed reviews.
The film is dedicated to Williams and Mickey Rooney,
who both died before its release.
The film explores themes of night watchman,
museum, natural history, smithsonian.
The tone is lighthearted.